### Privacy policy

#### 1\. General information

This privacy policy informs you about the processing of personal data in connection with our websites and online presences.

#### 2\. Who is officially responsible for processing the data?

**Hetzner Online GmbH**  
Industriestr. 25  
91710 Gunzenhausen  
Germany

You can find more information about our company in our [Legal Notice page](https://www.hetzner.com/legal/legal-notice/).

#### 3\. Who can you contact if you have questions regarding data protection?

You can reach out directly to our data protection officer using one of these methods:

**Email:** [data-protection@hetzner.com](mailto:data-protection@hetzner.com)

**Post:**  
Hetzner Online GmbH  
Datenschutz  
Industriestr. 25  
91710 Gunzenhausen  
Germany

**Phone:** +49 (0)9831 505216

**Fax:** +49 (0)3745 744472361

#### 4\. How do we process your personal data?

**Note:** Unless otherwise specified, your data will remain within the EU and will not be passed on to third parties.

#### [4.1 Applications](https://www.hetzner.com/dev/tasks/DevTasks-GenerateStaticPageTask#collapse_4-1)

###### What data will be processed and how does it reach Hetzner?

The type of data that we process may **change a bit depending on the job you are applying for and its requirements.** We process: basic personal information, career-conditions (e.g. notice period), education and work experience, professional knowledge, attached documents / attachments, if applicable, special categories of data (e.g. if you have a disability or special needs), information about your interview and notes on it, and additional information shared with us during the application process.  
We will obtain this data **directly from you** or – if a **recruitment agency** is involved – directly from the agency.

###### Why does Hetzner process my data and what is the legal basis for it?

*   **Conclusion of an employment contract:** Reviewing and processing your application. The goal is to sign an employment contract. (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR)
*   **Ensuring your protection rights:** Processing special categories of personal data to protect your legal rights. (Art. 9 para. 2 lit. b GDPR in connection with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR)
*   **Inclusion in our talent pool:** Storage of your documents for future positions in the company on the basis of your voluntary consent (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR). You can revoke your permission at any time by reaching out to our personnel team at: [career@hetzner.com](mailto:career@hetzner.com)
*   **Legal documentation:** Storing the data to protect against potential legal claims or to assert them if necessary. (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR)

###### How will my application data be managed?

All applications are entered into our **applicant management system.** If you applied by post, we will digitize your documents and return the originals to you.  
To process your application, a **candidate profile** will be created in the system. **You will not have access to this profile.**

###### Who will have access to my data and will it be sent to any third parties?

We use **external software from Rexx** for the application management system. This company acts as a service provider for us. They may access your data as part of maintaining the systems. We have concluded a data processing agreement (DPA) with this provider, which ensures that the data is processed only according to our instructions and in compliance with applicable data protection regulations.  
You can find more information in Rexx’s (Rexx Systems GmbH, Süderstrasse 75-79, 20097 Hamburg, Germany) privacy policy: [https://www.rexx-systems.com/datenschutz/](https://www.rexx-systems.com/datenschutz/).  
If your application does not match a position at Hetzner Online, we may check whether **another company in our group** (Hetzner Cloud GmbH, Hetzner Finland Oy) might be interested in your profile and whether sharing your application would benefit your career opportunities. Your documents will only be shared if the position is equivalent or similar to the one you applied for. (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR)  
If you do not agree to this, you can object at any time. Please contact our HR team: [career@hetzner.com](mailto:career@hetzner.com).

###### How long will my data be saved?

The length of time your data will be stored can vary depending on the results of your application process:

*   **Rejection or withdrawal of the application: Six** months after the rejection or withdrawal of your application.
*   **Storage in our talent pool: 24 months.** You can revoke your permission for this at any time. Please contact our HR team to do so: [career@hetzner.com](mailto:career@hetzner.com)
*   **You become an employee: Your personal data will become part of your employee file.**

Once the deadlines are reached, we will **delete** your data.

#### [4.2 Feedback](https://www.hetzner.com/dev/tasks/DevTasks-GenerateStaticPageTask#collapse_4-2)

##### 4.2.1 General feedback

You can give us feedback about our products and services via [https://feedback.hetzner.com/](https://feedback.hetzner.com/).

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

We process the information that you provide as part of your feedback. You do not need to provide any personal data.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

We use the feedback to **analyze and continuously improve our customer service**. (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)

###### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

Only **authorized Hetzner employees** have access to the feedback.

###### How long do we store the data?

**3 years** (in accordance with Sections 195, 199 German Civil Code (BGB)). We then delete the data.

##### 4.2.2 Feedback about our customer service

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

After a support contact has been completed, you can **voluntarily** give us feedback. **We process**:

*   Ticket number
*   the information that you provide in the free-text field

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

We use the feedback to **analyze and continuously improve our customer service**. (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)

###### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

Only **authorized Hetzner employees** have access to the feedback.

###### How long do we store the data?

**2 years**. We then **anonymize** the data.

##### 4.2.3 Feedback about products on experiments.hetzner.com

**General feedback**  
You can give us general feedback about our Experiments products via [https://experiments.hetzner.com/support](https://experiments.hetzner.com/support).

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

We process your **contact details** and the **product information connected with the experiment (e.g. API token)**.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

We use the feedback to **analyze and continuously improve our customer service**. (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)

###### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

Only **authorized Hetzner employees** have access to the feedback.

###### How long do we store the data?

**1 year**. We then anonymize the data.

**Feedback surveys**  
On our Experiments platform, you can test prototypes and possible future Hetzner products free of charge. It is particularly important for us to learn what works well, where there are problems and what we can improve. As part of your use of the platform, we may contact you to ask for your feedback.

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

You can **voluntarily** provide your **contact details** in our feedback form. You can also participate anonymously.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

We use the feedback to analyze and further develop our products. (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)

###### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

Only **authorized Hetzner employees** have access to the feedback.

###### How long do we store the data?

We store the contact details connected with the feedback for 2 years. We then anonymize the data.

#### [4.3 Forum](https://www.hetzner.com/dev/tasks/DevTasks-GenerateStaticPageTask#collapse_4-3)

In our [Forum](https://forum.hetzner.com/) users can discuss about technical topics and our services.

###### What data will be processed and how does it reach Hetzner?

If **you** register for our online forum, we store the **username you choose** and your **email address.**

###### Why does Hetzner process my data and what is the legal basis for it?

The forum serves as a communication platform for our community members. (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR)

###### How long will my data be saved?

After you **delete your forum account,** your data will also be **deleted immediately.**

#### [4.4 Prize Draws / Contests](https://www.hetzner.com/dev/tasks/DevTasks-GenerateStaticPageTask#collapse_4-4)

###### What data will be processed and how does it reach Hetzner?

If you participate in one of our prize draws, we process – **depending on the type of prize draw** – the following data: your first and last name, email address, postal address, and, if applicable, your social media username. This data is provided directly by **you,** e.g. via a form on our website or by interacting with our social media posts.

###### Why does Hetzner process my data and what is the legal basis for it?

We need this data to **carry out the prize draw,** and to **notify the winners.** (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR)

###### How long will my data be saved?

**After the prize draw has ended and the prizes have been sent,** we **delete** the related personal data.

#### [4.5 AI](https://www.hetzner.com/dev/tasks/DevTasks-GenerateStaticPageTask#collapse_4-5)

##### 4.5.1 Ask AI chatbot

An AI chatbot is integrated into this website. It can answer general questions about our products.  
If you have questions about your customer account, please contact us via [https://accounts.hetzner.com](https://accounts.hetzner.com/).

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

**Chatbot**  
We process the **information that you enter in the chat**. You do **not need to provide any personal data** to use the chatbot.

Your request is first sent to Hetzner and automatically checked for personal data (PII tool). Any personal data that is detected is removed before the request is sent to our external AI service. The external AI service then creates an answer and sends it back to Hetzner. If necessary, we add the previously removed personal data back to the answer. The answer is then shown to you in the chat.

If the chatbot cannot answer your question, you can **send us a support request**. In this case, we process:

*   Name
*   Email address
*   Customer number
*   Chat ID
*   AI-generated summary of your problem

For more information, please see the section **“Customer inquiries”**.

**Cookies**  
We use the cookies that are required for the general operation of our website. For more information, please see the section **“Website”**.

**Logfiles**  
We collect the **logfiles** that are required for the general operation of our website. For more information, please see the section **“Website”**.

In addition, we assign an internal identifier (**request ID**) to each request and record whether the request was processed successfully (status and error messages).

The external AI service also processes technical data that is required for the operation, security and monitoring of the service.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

We process the content of your request to **answer your questions**. (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)

We process technical data to ensure the **secure and reliable operation of the chatbot**. (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)

###### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

Your data is only accessible to **authorized Hetzner employees**.

We use an **external AI service** with servers located in the EU to provide the AI function. The provider only receives the previously cleaned request without personal data. The service provider processes the data only according to our instructions. We have concluded a contract with the provider to ensure compliance with data protection requirements.

Your requests are **not used to train or improve AI models**.

###### How long do we store the data?

*   **Chat histories and related logfiles**: 3 years (Sections 195, 199 German Civil Code (BGB))
*   **Logfiles at our external AI service**: up to 90 days
*   If you open a **support ticket**: Please see the section “Customer inquiries”.

##### 4.5.2 Inference

With Inference, we provide AI models that you can integrate into your applications via an application programming interface (API). **The AI models are operated entirely on our own Hetzner infrastructure**.

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

**Prompts and outputs**  
The **content of your request** (prompt) is sent to our Hetzner servers and processed there to generate an **answer** (output).

**Logfiles**  
When you use the API, we also store the following technical data in a logfile:

*   IP address (we store this in anonymized form)
*   Date and time of access
*   Metadata of the API request (including HTTP requests and status codes)
*   Settings selected by the user for the API request (e.g. the maximum length of the generated answer)

The content of your requests and answers is not included in the logfiles.

**Billing data**  
A Hetzner customer account is required to use Inference. The use of the AI service is billed via this account. In this context, we store the following **billing data**:

*   Project ID
*   Name of the API token (you can choose this yourself)
*   Time of the request
*   Number of input and output tokens processed

The content of your requests and answers is not included in the billing data.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

We process the content of your requests and the billing data to **provide the Inference service** and to bill you for its use. (Art. 6(1)(b) GDPR)

We process the logfiles to ensure the **secure and reliable operation of the service**. (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)

###### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

*   **Your requests and the answers are processed on our servers and do not leave the Hetzner infrastructure.**
*   Only **authorized Hetzner employees** have access to the **billing data** and **logfiles**.

###### How long do we store the data?

*   **Prompts and outputs**: Under our **zero-retention policy**, we do not store them. They are also not used in any other way to train or improve the AI models.
*   **Logfiles**: 6 months
*   **Billing data**: **8 years** (in accordance with statutory tax and commercial law retention requirements)

#### [4.6 Customer Account](https://www.hetzner.com/dev/tasks/DevTasks-GenerateStaticPageTask#collapse_4-6)

###### What data is processed and how does it reach Hetzner?

When creating a customer account, we process the **name, contact details, and payment information** that **you** provide to us. Your **IP address** is also automatically transmitted via your **browser.**

If you are invited to a **cloud project,** we store **only your email address.**

###### Why does Hetzner process my data and what is the legal basis for it?

We process your data **to create and manage your customer account.** This is necessary to give you access to our products and services. (Art. 6. para. 1 lit. b GDPR)

###### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

**We do not collect or store any credit card information.** You enter this information directly to our **external payment provider Computop.** For more information, please refer to the privacy notice of Computop Paygate GmbH (Schwarzenbergstr. 4, 96050 Bamberg, Germany): [https://computop.com/us/data-protection](https://computop.com/us/data-protection).

To make future payments easier, a **pseudocard number** is saved in your customer account.

If we register a **domain** for you, we pass on the necessary data to the respective registry (depending on the domain).

If you fail to pay despite repeated reminders, we may instruct the **debt collection company Intrum** to collect the outstanding debt. Intrum acts as an independent controller. For more information, please refer to the privacy notice of Intrum Deutschland GmbH (Donnersbergstraße 1, 64646 Heppenheim, Germany): [https://www.intrum.de/zahlungserinnerung-erhalten/uber-intrum/datenschutz/](https://www.intrum.de/zahlungserinnerung-erhalten/uber-intrum/datenschutz/).

###### How long will my data be saved?

After a customer account is deactivated, the following retention periods apply:

*   **Without product usage: 3 years**
*   **With product usage (invoicing): 14 years** (in accordance with tax and commercial law retention obligations)
*   **Unverified customer accounts: 14 days** after the end of the failed verification period

Once these periods have expired, your **data will be deleted.**

##### 4.6.1 Verification of customer information

**4.6.1.1 New customers**

To minimize our business risk and prevent fraud, we carry out a **risk assessment** when new customer accounts are registered.

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

Based on defined criteria and our experience, we assess how likely it is that you will meet your contractual payment obligations and use our services responsibly.

In particular, we consider the **registration data you provide, technical characteristics** and, where applicable, **information from existing or previous contractual relationships**. We also use an external service provider to support the risk assessment.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

We process your data to **minimize our business risk** and to **prevent fraud**. (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)

###### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

Our **employees responsible for this process** have access to the data.

We also use an external service provider to support the risk assessment. For security reasons, we do not provide information about the specific assessment criteria or how they are weighted, as this could make it easier for users to create fake accounts or misuse our services.

###### How long do we store your data?

The **result of the assessment** is stored in your customer account for the **duration of the customer relationship**.

For information about the retention and deletion periods for customer accounts, please see the section "Customer account".

###### Further information about the risk assessment

The result of the risk assessment is considered as one of several factors in the decision. **The final decision** on whether a customer account is activated **is always made by one of our employees responsible for this process and is therefore not based solely on automated processing.**

For security reasons, we do not provide specific details about why a verification was unsuccessful. We also do not disclose the underlying logic of the process, as this could make it easier for users to create fake accounts or misuse our services.

**If you would like us to review a decision made in connection with the risk assessment, you can contact [cda-review@hetzner.com](mailto:cda-review@hetzner.com).**

**4.6.1.2 Existing customers**

To prevent payment defaults and fraud and to protect our services, we carry out an **ongoing risk assessment** during the customer relationship based on defined criteria and our experience.

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

In particular, we process **information about the existing business relationship**, such as previous payment behavior, orders and previous use of our products and services.  
When reviewing individual orders, we may also ask you to provide information about how you plan to use our products.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

We process this data to **prevent payment defaults**, to **prevent fraud** and to **protect our services**. (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)

###### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

Our **employees responsible for this process** have access to the data. The data is not shared with third parties.

###### How long do we store your data?

The result of the assessment is stored in your customer account for the **duration of the customer relationship** and is **continuously updated**. For information about the retention and deletion periods for customer accounts, please see the section "Customer account".

We store information that you provide to us as part of an order review for three years. (Sections 195, 199 German Civil Code (BGB))

###### Further information about the risk assessment

**The final decision** about which products or services can be ordered, which order or usage limits apply and which functions are available within the customer account **is always made by one of our employees responsible for this process and is therefore not based solely on automated processing.**

**4.6.1.3 Identity verification**

In individual cases, we may ask you to verify your identity using a valid identity document. The verification is carried out by one of our employees or by our external service provider iDenfy.  
iDenfy acts as a processor for us, and we have concluded a data processing agreement with the company.

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

*   **Identity verification by Hetzner**: From the identity document **you provide**, we receive the following information: **name, address and expiry date of the document**. **Other information in the identity document can be blacked out.**
*   **Identity verification by iDenfy**: For information about the data collected by iDenfy, **please see the company's privacy policy**: iDenfy UAB (K. Baršausko g. 59, LT-51423 Kaunas, Lithuania): **[https://www.idenfy.com/privacy-policy/](https://www.idenfy.com/privacy-policy/)**. We receive the verification result afterwards.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

Identity verification is carried out to **prevent fraud and payment defaults** and to **protect our services against misuse**. (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)

In addition, the verification is carried out to **perform the contract**, as you are required to provide proof that your information is correct if we request it. (Art. 6(1)(b) GDPR in conjunction with section 2.3 of our Terms and Conditions)

###### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

*   **Identity verification by Hetzner**: Only **our employees responsible for this process** have access to the data. The data is not shared with third parties.
*   **Identity verification by iDenfy**: We **send your name and the country where you live to iDenfy**. **However, the data is only transferred when you click the verification link.**

###### How long do we store your data?

*   **Identity verification by Hetzner**: Your data is **deleted immediately** after the verification.
*   **Identity verification by iDenfy**: The provider stores your data for **two months**. An individual exception to this automated deletion and retention process is currently not possible. This also applies if no customer relationship is established after the identity verification has been completed.

##### 4.6.2 Customer inquiries

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

**When you send us an inquiry**, we process in particular the **following data**:

*   Customer number
*   Email address
*   For questions about a product: the related product or project ID
*   Other personal data that you provide in your inquiry, e.g. an invoice number.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

We process your data **to answer your inquiry** and to support you with questions about existing or new products. (Art. 6(1)(b) GDPR).

###### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

Access is limited to **authorized Hetzner employees**.

###### How long do we store the data?

We store the data for **3 years** (Sections 195, 199 German Civil Code (BGB)) and then delete it.

##### 4.6.3 One-Time Password

If you log in to your customer account from a new device or an unusual location, we send you a one-time password (OTP).

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

We process the following data for each login attempt:

*   Customer number
*   Date and time
*   IP address
*   Type of login (OTP or 2FA)
*   Information about whether the login was successful

The data is **collected automatically** when you log in.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

We process the data to protect your customer account from unauthorized access. (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)

###### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

Your data is only accessible to **authorized Hetzner employees**.

###### How long do we store the data?

We use the data from the last **100 days** to check login attempts.

##### 4.6.4 Verification of domain holder data

Due to legal cybersecurity requirements, DENIC eG, as the central registry for .de domains, is required to ensure that correct and reachable holder data is available for every .de domain.

If DENIC has doubts about the accuracy or validity of the holder data stored for your domain, we as the registrar are required to verify this information.

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

For **private individuals**, we require **proof of your identity and address** to verify your holder data. You can provide this proof, for example, with an identity document, a registration certificate or a utility bill.

For companies, we also require **additional proof of the company**, for example an extract from the commercial register.

The documents are provided **by you** directly to Hetzner **after we have asked you to verify the data**.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

We process the data to **verify the accuracy** of the **holder data** provided when the domain was registered and to **send the result of the verification to DENIC**.

We process the data to comply with a legal obligation. (Art. 6(1)(c) GDPR in conjunction with the legal requirements for the verification of domain holder data and the related requirements of DENIC.)

###### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

Only the **Hetzner employees responsible for the verification** have access to the documents.

We **only send the result of the verification** and, where applicable, updated holder data **to DENIC**.

**The documents you provide as proof are not shared with DENIC.**

###### How long do we store the data?

The documents you provide as proof are **deleted immediately after the verification has been completed**.

###### Further information

Hetzner has no influence on DENIC's review and cannot provide information about why or which data was marked as invalid.

If the required documents are not provided or the holder data cannot be confirmed, DENIC may take measures up to and including deactivation and deletion of the domain.

##### 4.6.5 Debt collection

If you do not pay despite repeated payment reminders, we may instruct the debt collection company Intrum (Intrum Deutschland GmbH, Donnersbergstraße 1, 64646 Heppenheim, Germany) to collect the outstanding amount.

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Intrum?

**We transfer the following data** to Intrum:

*   Contact details
*   VAT identification number (VAT ID)
*   Customer number
*   Case number
*   Invoice number, date and amount

At Intrum's request, we may also provide further information required to collect the outstanding amount, e.g. invoices, payment reminders, dunning notices and termination notices.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

We transfer the data to **enforce our payment claims**. (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)

###### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

At Hetzner, only **authorized Hetzner employees** have access.

To collect outstanding amounts, we transfer the required data to Intrum. Intrum processes the transferred data under its own responsibility. For more information, please see Intrum's privacy information: [https://www.intrum.de/zahlungserinnerung-erhalten/](https://www.intrum.de/zahlungserinnerung-erhalten/)

###### How long do we store the data?

We store the data held by us for **eight years** due to statutory retention requirements. (Section 257 German Commercial Code (HGB), Section 147 German Fiscal Code (AO))

##### 4.6.6 Abuse reports

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

We process the personal data that you provide to us as part of **your abuse report**.

In particular, we process:

*   **Name**
*   **Email address**
*   **Other personal data** that you provide in the **report** or in **attachments**

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

We process your personal data to **handle your abuse report**. (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)

###### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

Your personal data is only accessible to **employees who need it to handle your abuse report**.

Depending on the affected product, we may need to **forward your abuse report to the affected Hetzner customer**, as we do not have access to the affected systems for all products.

If, during our review, we find that your abuse report needs to be forwarded and the affected Hetzner customer cannot handle it without receiving your name and email address, we share this data based on the **consent** you gave in the abuse form. (Art. 6(1)(a) GDPR) If you have not given us your consent, we will first ask you for it. If you do not give your consent, we may close your abuse report without further processing.

###### How long do we store the data?

We store the abuse report for a **maximum of ten years**.

If the data is required to establish, exercise or defend legal claims, we will only delete it after the relevant proceedings have been completed.

#### [4.7 Newsletter](https://www.hetzner.com/dev/tasks/DevTasks-GenerateStaticPageTask#collapse_4-7)

In our newsletter, we inform you about new products and current topics.

##### 1\. Newsletter registration

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

When you register for our newsletter, **you** provide us with your **email address**. You can also voluntarily provide your name and job profile when you register.  
We store the **date of registration** in the background. In addition, **your browser automatically sends** us your **IP address**.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

Registration for the newsletter is voluntary. After you register, we send you a **double opt-in** link. You use this link to confirm that you want to receive our newsletter in the future. This means that your registration is only successfully completed after you click the link in the confirmation email. (Art. 6(1)(a) GDPR)

###### How long do we store the data?

You must confirm that you want to receive the newsletter within **30 days**. If you do not confirm within this period, we delete your data.

If you confirm that you want to receive the newsletter, we store your data, including the double opt-in, **until you unsubscribe** from the newsletter. For more information, please see the section "Unsubscribing from the newsletter".

##### 2\. Sending the newsletter

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

When we send our newsletter, we store the complete content of the email, including the subject, the recipient's email address and the recipient's name (**email preview**).  
We also store **technical events**, such as the status of the email (e.g. "sent") and error messages.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

We store this data to ensure that our **newsletter is sent correctly**. (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)

###### How long do we store the data?

We store the data for **24 months** and then delete it.

##### 3\. Tracking

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

Our newsletter contains **tracking pixels** that are loaded from the server of our newsletter service provider when you open the newsletter.  
In this context, we record whether, when and how often you open the newsletter (**open rate and time of opening**) and which links you click and how often (**click behavior and click rate**). We also process the **date**, **email address** and **IP address**.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

We use tracking to continuously improve our newsletter and adapt it to the interests of our readers. In particular, we evaluate this data in aggregated form.  
We process the data based on your **consent**, which you gave when you registered for the newsletter. (Art. 6(1)(a) GDPR).

You can withdraw your consent at any time with effect for the future by using the unsubscribe link in the newsletter.

###### How long do we store the data?

We store the data for **24 months** and then delete it.

##### 4\. Unsubscribing from the newsletter

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

When you unsubscribe from the newsletter, we store the **date of your unsubscribe request** and link it to your registration data (name, email address, job profile, double opt-in).

In addition, we add your email address to our blocklist (**blacklist**) so that we do not send you newsletters in the future.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

We process this data to **document your unsubscribe request** and to **prevent newsletters from being sent to your email address again**. (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)

###### How long do we store the data?

We store the **data used as proof of your unsubscribe request, including the data you provided when you registered**, for **3 years after you unsubscribe** (Sections 195, 199 German Civil Code (BGB)) and then delete it.  
We store your **email address permanently on the blacklist** to prevent newsletters from being sent to you again. (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)

##### 5\. Other

At trade fairs, you can provide us with your **trade fair badge** to receive information about our company in the future.

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

We process the contact details that we receive when we **scan your trade fair badge** (usually your **name, email address and job profile**).

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

By **voluntarily** providing your trade fair badge for scanning, we process your data to **register you for our newsletter** and to **send you the promo code**. (Art. 6(1)(a) GDPR)

###### How long do we store the data?

The **link between** the **promo code and your data** is removed after **two months**.

We store your **contact details** for **sending the newsletter** until you withdraw your consent to receive the newsletter. For more information, please see the section "Newsletter registration".

##### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

Our **employees responsible for marketing** may access your data.

For the registration, management and sending of our newsletter, as well as the related processing activities described above, we use an **external digital marketing service provider**. We have concluded a data processing agreement with this provider in accordance with Art. 28 GDPR. This agreement ensures that the data is only processed according to our instructions and in compliance with the applicable data protection laws.

#### [4.8 Hetzner Status](https://www.hetzner.com/dev/tasks/DevTasks-GenerateStaticPageTask#collapse_4-8)

You can find general status reports on our products and services via our [status page](https://status.hetzner.com/).

###### What personal data is processed and how does it reach Hetzner?

When **you sign up** for notifications, you provide us with your **email address.**

###### Why and on what legal basis is the data processed?

We process your data in order to **notify you about service disruptions and maintenance activities.** (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR)

###### How long is the data stored?

The data is **deleted as soon as you unsubscribe** from the notification service.

#### [4.9 Social Media](https://www.hetzner.com/dev/tasks/DevTasks-GenerateStaticPageTask#collapse_4-9)

##### Facebook

Provider: Meta Platforms Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour Dublin 2, Ireland.  
Privacy Policy: [https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/)  
Opt-Out: [https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads](https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads).

We operate a company page on Facebook. The following information applies to you when you visit our Facebook page.

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

**Interaction with us**  
If you interact with us, for example through comments, likes or messages, we process your username, publicly available profile information and the content of your interaction.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

*   for our public relations activities (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)
*   to communicate with users (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)

###### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

The data is processed by both us and Meta. Personal data may be transferred to third countries, in particular to the USA.

###### How long do we store the data?

We do not store access data from your visit ourselves. Content and interactions remain stored on Facebook until they are deleted by you or by the platform provider. Meta's retention periods are based on its privacy policy.

##### Instagram

Provider: Meta Platforms Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour Dublin 2, Ireland.  
Privacy Policy: [https://instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/](https://instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/)  
Opt-Out: [https://instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/](https://instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/)

We operate a profile on Instagram. The following information applies to you when you visit our Instagram page.

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

**Interaction with us**  
If you interact with us, for example through comments, likes or messages, we process your username, publicly visible profile information and the content of your interaction.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

*   for our public relations activities (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)
*   to communicate with users (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)

###### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

The data is processed by both us and Meta. Personal data may be transferred to third countries, in particular to the USA.

###### How long do we store the data?

We do not store access data ourselves. Content and interactions remain stored on the platform until they are deleted. Other retention periods are based on Meta's requirements.

##### X

Provider: Twitter International Unlimited Company, One Cumberland Place, Fenian Street Dublin 2, D02 AX07 Ireland.  
Privacy Policy: [https://twitter.com/de/privacy](https://twitter.com/de/privacy)  
Opt-Out: [https://help.twitter.com/de/safety-and-security/privacy-controls-for-tailored-ads](https://help.twitter.com/de/safety-and-security/privacy-controls-for-tailored-ads)

We operate a profile on X. The following information applies to you when you visit our X page.

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

**Interaction with us**  
If you interact with us, for example through tweets, replies or direct messages, we process your username, publicly available profile information and the content of your interaction.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

*   for our public relations activities (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)
*   to communicate with users (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)

###### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

The data is processed by the provider X. Personal data may be processed worldwide and transferred to third countries, in particular to the USA.

###### How long do we store the data?

We do not store access data ourselves. Content and interactions remain stored on the platform until they are deleted. The provider determines the specific retention periods.

##### YouTube

Provider: Google Ireland Limited (Gordon House, Barrow Street Dublin 4, Ireland)  
Privacy Policy: [https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)  
Opt-Out: [https://youtube.com/opt-out](https://youtube.com/opt-out).

We operate a channel on YouTube. The following information applies to you when you visit our YouTube channel.

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

**Interaction with us**  
If you interact with us, for example through comments or likes, we process your username, publicly visible profile information and the content of your interaction.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

*   for our public relations activities (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)
*   to communicate with users (Art. 6(1)(f) GDPR)

###### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

The data is processed by us and by Google. Personal data may be transferred to third countries, in particular to the USA.

###### How long do we store the data?

We do not store access data ourselves. Content and interactions remain stored on YouTube until they are deleted. The retention periods are based on Google's requirements.

#### [4.10 Events](https://www.hetzner.com/dev/tasks/DevTasks-GenerateStaticPageTask#collapse_4-10)

##### Registration and participation in events

###### What data is processed and how does it reach Hetzner?

The data we process **depends on the type of event** and may include: **name, contact details, and additional information** such as food allergies, T-shirt size, or date of birth. We receive this data directly from **you** during the registration process.

###### Why does Hetzner process my data and what is the legal basis for it?

We process your data to **organize and carry out your participation** in the event. (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR)

###### How long will my data be saved?

We at Hetzner will **delete** the data relevant to the event **after the event is completely over.**

##### Photos and videos

During our events, we take **photos and videos**. We mainly take **photos that focus on the event rather than on individual people**. We use these photos and videos for **publication on our social media channels**, in our **internal communication channels** (intranet, employee magazine), and in our [press section](https://www.hetzner.com/press-release/).

As many people may attend our events and we mainly take overview and group photos, we cannot completely rule out that you may appear in a photo or video. If you are recognizable in a published photo or video and do not want it to remain published, you can contact us at **[event@hetzner.com](mailto:event@hetzner.com)** and let us know which photo or video you are referring to. We will review your request and, where appropriate, take suitable action.

Please note that when **photos and videos are published on the internet, they can be stored and accessed worldwide**. We therefore cannot completely rule out that third parties may continue to use them or that they may still be found through search engines, even after we have removed them from our social media channels.

#### [4.11 Video surveillance](https://www.hetzner.com/dev/tasks/DevTasks-GenerateStaticPageTask#collapse_4-11)

###### What data do we process and how does it reach Hetzner?

As part of our video surveillance, we process **video recordings** of people who **enter the monitored area**.

###### Why do we process the data and what is the legal basis?

We use video surveillance to **protect our property**, in particular to prevent and investigate criminal offenses (e.g. theft or vandalism) and to exercise our rights as the owner of the premises.

###### Who has access to the data and is it shared with third parties?

The recordings are only accessible to **employees who need access to perform their tasks**. **We only share the recordings with third parties where this is legally permitted or required**, for example with law enforcement authorities or courts.

###### How long do we store my data?

The recordings are **deleted immediately as soon as they are no longer required for the purposes stated above**.

#### [4.12 Website](https://www.hetzner.com/dev/tasks/DevTasks-GenerateStaticPageTask#collapse_4-12)

##### Logfiles

###### What data is processed and how does it reach Hetzner?

When you access our website, **your browser** automatically sends the following data: **IP address, browser type and version, date and time of access, the website you came from, and the specific page accessed.**

###### Why does Hetzner process my data and what is the legal basis for it?

We process this data to **ensure the secure and stable operation of our website.** (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR)

###### How long is the data stored?

Since the **IP address is stored in anonymized form,** no retention period is required.

##### Website analysis (cookies)

###### What data is processed and how does it reach Hetzner?

If you consent to the **use of all cookies when visiting our website,** we use **Matomo** to analyze user behavior. Cookies are stored and the following data is processed: **IP address, pages visited, time spent on each page, browser used, and the site you visited before ours.** This data is automatically **transmitted by your browser.**

You **can prevent the storage of cookies** (both necessary and non-essential) by adjusting your browser settings. However, please note that doing so may limit functionality on our website.

You can later deactivate non-essential cookies via: Show Preferences.

###### Why does Hetzner process my data and what is the legal basis for it?

The data is collected to **optimize our website.** Processing is based on your consent (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR).

###### How long is the data stored?

The **IP address is stored in anonymized form.** A personal reference is no longer possible.

#### 5\. What rights do I have when it comes to my data?

The GDPR grants you the following rights regarding your data:

*   **Right of access:**  
    You can request information at any time about whether and which personal data we process about you.
*   **Right to rectification:**  
    If the data we have stored about you is incorrect or incomplete, you can request its correction or completion.
*   **Right to erasure ("right to be forgotten"):**  
    You can request the deletion of your data if it is no longer required for its original purpose. However, please note that immediate deletion may not be possible in some cases due to legal or contractual retention obligations.
*   **Right to restriction of processing:**  
    If, for example, you dispute the accuracy of your data or believe that the processing is unlawful, you can request that we restrict the processing of your data.
*   **Right to data portability:**  
    You have the right to receive your data in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format. You can also request that we transfer the data directly to a third party, if technically feasible.
*   **Right to object:**  
    You can object to the processing of your personal data unless there are compelling legitimate reasons for the processing.
*   **Right not to be subject to automated decision-making:**  
    We do not make any automated decisions regarding your person. If we did, you would have the right not to be evaluated solely by algorithms.

**If you would like to make use of any of these rights, please contact our data protection officer directly.**

#### 6\. Making complaints to the relevant data protection authority

If you believe that we are violating any data protection laws by processing personal data, you also have the right to make a complaint to the data supervisory authority who is responsible for our company.  
**However, we encourage you to first contact our data protection officer.** We always strive to resolve any possible disagreements as quickly and smoothly as possible so that we can avoid conflicts.

#### 7\. Voluntary nature of data provision

There is no statutory obligation for you to provide your data to Hetzner Online GmbH. However, you cannot use some of our services if you do not provide your data to us. Your decision to provide us with your personal data is completely voluntary.

#### 8\. General note

We reserve the right to update this privacy policy from time to time. If you visit this page again, the updated privacy policy will apply.

**Status: September 14, 2026**
